I'm a fan of the original Ultraman.
I would say I like it
more than Ultra Seven.
What did you like the most about it?
My favorite were the Alien Zarab.
Alien Zarab.
They're minor characters though.
I like that they're the exact
opposite of Ultraman.
Coming to Earth is part of their job.
Destroying humans and
destroying other life forms is their job.
That's what I liked about them.
They show that there are aliens that
are on the opposite side of Ultraman.
I also like the imitation Ultras.
I love fakes.
No one can tell the difference.
You can usually tell between
two different kinds of cats.
It's a lot more difficult
when dealing with aliens.
There's barely any differences.
Weren't there a lot of imitations
that had slight color variations?
Their scarf would be yellow, or
they'd have black on their uniform.
All they had to do
was change their color.
What is Ultraman doing?
Different page from the same book.
Yeah, the same book.
Just folded weirdly.
You get the feeling that
the fakes could take over.
Which kaiju do you like the best?
It's gotta be Neronga.
Neronga.
Oh, and Dodongo.
Dodongo.
Anno, how about you?
Oh, I like Ultraman.
My favorite is the original Ultraman.
What about kaiju?
I'm not all that interested in kaiju.
Really?
You weren't paying attention to them.
I saw them at least.
There was a night scene with a green
kaiju and a building between them.
That was cool.
That's what you were watching.
What exactly did you
like about Ultraman?
Hmm, what is it about
the original Ultraman?
He's an alien.
Yes.
It's amazing, yet makes you
feel a little uncomfortable.
In the A-type, it felt like
he was a person.
His lips were slightly
parted, and it was scary.
The A-type Ultraman
was frightening to me as a kid.
I wondered if there was a person
like that somewhere in the world.
After he collided with officer
Hayate, before he fused with him,
he was laughing like, "Ha ha
ha, there is nothing to fear."
That's easy for an alien to say.
They eventually came out with not
only A-type but also B-type and C-type.
Which do you prefer?
I like B-type.
Which one was B-type?
This area kind of all flowed together
upward in an aesthetically pleasing way.
Combat-wise he has the best exterior.
I like how strong he looks.
He's muscular.
The muscles.
B-type.
He looks the most like a hero.
Doesn't his mouth move sometimes?
A-type has the wrinkly part at his mouth.
A-type?
His mouth and body are probably
masked with a skintight material,
so it gives off the feeling that he's naked.
Didn't he initially have the gimmick
to open and close his mouth?
Along that line of thought though...
It doesn't really look like a mask.
It was his face.
B-type has the hard mask so it looks like
a person wearing a wetsuit and mask.
When the first suit was all wrinkled
up, it ended up looking like skin.
Just imagine watching
Hide fighting naked.
Wait...
That's the feeling.
That mental image...
Is that pattern supposed to be pants?
That's the feeling.
They're styled like blood flow.
He doesn't have any muscles either.
All he has is an arbitrary
pattern right here.
Furuya Bin's physique is scary.
That's where our
conversation has led us.
I guess his posture is
what stands out more.
The Specium Ray pose.
It was the beginning of that famous pose.
Did you think the
Specium Ray was cool?
As a gimmick?
Up until then, crossing your arms to
produce a beam hadn't been done.
That was cool.
Amazing. Absolutely brilliant.
To think a beam would release
from crossing your arms like this.
Ok, so, all of you have
worked as directors before.
If you were to direct an Ultraman series,
what kind of story would you create?
I would want to redo the Earth
Defense Force adequately.
Adequately? Just the EDF?
I want to focus on that organization.
The organization?
Yeah, I want to run the organization
through all kinds of situations.
Is that so?
The stars from the originals
wouldn't have to show up.
Like who?
Ultraman. I mean, he can show
up at the end, for the final scene.
Jeez.
What a cheeky thing to say.
I would want to revitalize the characters.
Properly revitalize the aliens.
Like the Baltan?
Yeah, even all the Ultras
would be great to revamp.
As is, Ultraman is fantastic. The
whole world gladly accepts him.
But, he clearly isn't living
in our current reality.
That's for sure.
Humans haven't joined hands to create
world peace or anything like that, yet.
If Ultraman showed up we'd ask, "What
are you going to do? What's your role?"
That's something I think about a lot.
Would humans today lend him a hand?
But that isn't really Ultraman.
That's true,
You had the chance to watch
Ultra Q and the original Ultraman.
What kind of influence do
you think that had on you?
If it weren't for Ultraman, I don't
think I would be in this line of work.
Really?
I'm here because it
affected my generation.
I wouldn't be here without Ultraman. I'd
be doing something completely different.
Seeing it had a
significant impact on me.
I'm a bit removed
from your generation,
but I think it was pivotal that it
captured people like me as well.
What we loved won't be as beloved by
kids 3 or 4 generations down the line.
Simply put, we have to put our best
foot forward so that kids watching now
will look up to our work and want to
make their own when they grow up.
That's the kind of position we hold.
That's true.
True.
That's the kind of position we hold.
Long ago, I fit into part of this costume.
Up to my wrist was fine, but trying
to fit my stomach was a problem.
That was fun.